Guide to the Jay Haley Collection, 1957-2007 M1733
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Haley's Writings, 1958-2003
  - Subseries 2.7 Schizophrenia, 1950-2007
    - Reprints 1960s: "Observation of the Family of the Schizophrenic"; "Control in Psychotherapy with Schizophrenics"; "The Art of Being Schizophrenic"; "Testing Parental Instructions to Schizophrenic and Normal Children"; "Toward a Theory of Pathological Systems", 1960-1968 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Psychotherapy of Schizophrenia. Philadelphia Meeting, April 21- 23; Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - A Tribute to Sullivan. The Doctor as Part of the Schizophrenia Interchange, (annotated typescripts), 1967 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Schizophrenics Deserve Family Therapy Not Dangerous Drugs and Management," (newspaper clipping), 1988 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "The Effect of Long-Term Outcome Studies on the Therapy of Schizophrenia," (reprints, typescript, and correspondence), 1989 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence on the Publication of Articles on Schizophrenia, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - On the CME Training Meeting (letters, typescript of talk), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Schizophrenia. Severely Disturbed Patients; Talk on Meichenbaum's "Core Tasks of Psychotherapy";The Therapy of Milton H. Erickson. Topical Panel, (typescripts of talks), circa 2004 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Undated Typescripts: Schizophrenia Communication: A Theoretical Discussion and a Proposal for Research; Alternative Views of "Schizophrenia" and their Consequences to Therapy; Improbable Solutions to Impossible Problems; The Good News on Schizophrenia; Interaction of Male Schizophrenia and their Parents; The Pathological System and Cross Cultural Measurement; Maneuvers in Induction. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2.8 Sexual Abuse, n.d.
    - The Therapy of Sexual Abuse; The Nature of the Crime; Offering Solutions; Kinds of Sex Abuse; Fragment of a Haley and Grove Interview, (typescripts) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2.9 Hierarchies and Power Tactics
    - Correspondence, Reviews, and Notes on The Power Tactics of Jesus Christ, 1962-1974 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Art of Being the Messiah, (typescripts) (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Power Tactics of Jesus Christ, (seven typescripts of different versions, mostly all annotated), circa 1965-1974 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Japanese and Hierarchy in Therapy, (correspondence, two annotated typescripts, and typescript fragments), 1999-2001 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Japanese and Hierarchy in Therapy, (complete annotated typescripts; different versions and incomplete typescripts; misc. pages), circa 2001 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Hierarchy Issues and Japanese; Hierarchy Issues and Therapy. Unpublished, (late versions of paper, annotated typescripts). Based on a research paper from 1967., circa 2001 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - A Proposal for Research to Develop a Taxonomy of Power Tactics, (typescript); The Development of a Taxonomy of Human Tactics, (mimiographed copies of typescript) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2.10 Feminism, 1985
    - How Should a Gentleman Talk to a Feminist Family Therapist, (annotated typescript) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Should Feminists be Allowed to do Family Therapy? (correspondence and annotated typescript), 1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2.11 Cross-Cultural Experiments, 1965-1968
    - "Cross-Cultural Experimentation: An Initial Attempt," (correspondence, annotated typescripts, and reprints); "Reaction to Socio-Documentary Film Research in a Mental Health Clinic," (journal), 1965-1971 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Sweet Sixteen. A Black Girl's Life, (annotated typescripts), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2.12 Media, Violence, 1952 - 1971
    - Violence in Films: “The Appeal of the Moving Picture,” (journal issue); Rating Parameters of Films, (typescripts), 1952 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Analysis of Social Themes and Group Structure in Popular Fictional Television Series. Research Proposal, (typescript), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Television Grant: An Approach for Categorizing Television Content with Special Relevance to Violence, (typescript and correspondence), 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Materials on Media and Violence. “New York Television,” by Dallas W. Smythe, Robert K. Merton, 1951,1952 (photocopies of article); Thesis, “Man and Society in Mass-Media Fiction: The Pattern of Life in the Mass Media as Revealed by Content-Analysis,” by Herbert Goodrich, n.d. (typescript of fragment); “Achieving Goals Through Violence on Television,” by Otto N. Larsen, Louis N. Gray, and Gerald Fortis, (photocopies of publication); “Four Years of New York Television 1951-1954,” by the Purdue Opinion Panel, (photocopies of publication); Haley’s notes of previous studies on media and violence, (typescript), 1951-1968; Although most of this material is not written by Haley it is included here, as part of series 2, because he filed it together with the notes he wrote about media and violence. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.13 Haley on Peers’ Writings, 1965-1996
    - Reviews/Introductions by Haley: “Where’s the Family?” on Salvador Minuchin’s paper, “Where is the Family in Narrative Family Therapy,” n.d. (typescript); On Donald Meichenbaum’s “Core Tasks of Psychotherapy,” n.d. (typescript); Three Book Reviews by Haley: Agoraphobia in the Light of Ego Psychology, by Edoardo Weiss; The Modes and Morals of Psychotherapy by Perry London; Games People Play, by Eric Berne, (photocopies of published review); Thomas S. Szasz, The Ethics of Psychoanalysis. Book reveiw, 1965, (typescript and correspondence); “Book Note” on Thomas Szasz, Law, Liberty and Psychotherapy: An Inquiry into the Social Uses of Mental Health Practices, 1965, (photocopies of journal); “Discussion,” on Judd Marmor’s "The Evolution of an Analytic Psychotherapist: A sixty-Year Search for Conceptual Clarity in the Tower of Babel," 1997, (photocopies of journal); Introduction for Michael Yapko's book, Hand-Me-Down Blues, 1998, (typescript and fax), 1965-1998 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2.14 Fiction and General Topics Journalism, 1947 - 1962
    - The Trial of Jesus Christ. A Three Act Play, (annotated typescripts), circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - An Anxious Husband and an Erring Wife. A One-Hour Teleplay, (typescript), circa 1960 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - The Red and the Black. A Live Television Play. Adapted from the novel by Stendahl or Marie-Henri Beyle, (typescript) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Black Jeanne. Play in Two Acts, (annotated typescript) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Don Quixote. Play in Two Acts, (annotated typescript) (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Poona. Play in Three Acts, (annotated typescript) (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Published articles and stories: Ye Cannot Serve Both God and Mammon; Cup of Bitterness; Students of the World, Unite! 1946, The Daily Bruin, (newspaper clippings); Stanford Man Views Movie 18 times -- All For Science, 1954, Daily Palo Alto Times, (newspaper clipping). “The Eastern Question,” 1947, (issue of New Yorker magazine); “Charlie and the Fire Extinguisher,” 1952, (issue of Bluebook magazine); “The Great Snafu,” 1954 (issue of Cavalier magazine), 1946-1954 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - The Real Truth About Love. Story, (typescripts) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Black Militancy: A National Effort. Article, (typescript) (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Oomgowuh Black Powuh. Article, (annotated typescript); Whither the Black Revolutionary. Article, (annotated typescript) (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - The Lake of Gold. Story, (annotated typescript) (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - The Robe and Bowl. Story, (annotated typescript), circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - The Lord as a Linear Thinker, (typescript) (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous: The Amiable Hippie, 1968, (annotated journal leaf); The Art of Being a Scientist, (typescript); Natural Conflicts in Business Management, (typescript), 1968-1998 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2.15 Haley’s Books in Various Languages, 1973-2007
    - Spanish Translations: Tratamiento de la Familia, 1974; Las Tácticas de Poder de Jesucristo y Otros Ensayos, 1991; Aprender y Enseñar Terapia, 1997; Terapia de Ordalía. Caminos Inusuales Para Modificar la Conducta, 2001; Técnicas de Terapia Familiar, con Lynn Hoffman, 2001; Terapia No Convencional. Las Técnicas Psiquiátricas de Milton H. Erickson, 2001; Terapia Para Resolver Problemas, 2001; El Arte de la Terapia Estratégica, con Madeleine Richeport-Haley, 2006; Italian Translations: Le Strategie Della Psicoterapia, 1974; Techniche de Terapia della Familgia, 1974; Il Distacco Dalla Familglia. La Crisi del Giovane e la Terapia della Famiglia, 1983; Cambiare i Bambini e le Famiglie. Conversazioni con Milton H. Erickson, 1988; Dietro lo Specchio. Problemi Ingarbugliati e Soluzioni Originali Nella Terapia della Famiglia, 1995; Strateghi del Potere. Gesù Cristo, lo Psicoanalista, lo Schizofrenico e Altri Ancora, 2009., 1974-2006 (Box 47)
    - French Translations: Changer les Couples. Conversations Avec Milton H. Erickson, 1990; Tacticiens du Pouvoir. Jésus-Christ, le Psychanalyste, le Schizophrène et Quelques Autres, 1991; Strategies de la Psychotherapie, 1993; Strategies de la Psychotherapie, 1993; Un Thérapeute Hors du Commun: Milton H. Erickson, 1995; D'un âge à l'autre: Thérapie familiale directive et cycle de vie, 2009; Swedish Translations: Psykoterapi-Strategi Och Teknik, 1975; Familje Terapi- Hur Man Löser Problem, 1979; Flytta Hemifrån. Familjeterapi Med Störda Ungdomar, 1982; German Translations: Die Psychotherapie Milton H. Ericksons, 1978; Ablösungsprobleme Jugendlicher. Familientherapie-Beispiele- Lösungen, 1981; Die Jesus-Strategie. Die Macht der Ohnmächtigen, 1990; Therapie Lehren & Lernen, 1999; Czech Translations: Neobvyklá Psychoterapie Miltona H. Ericksona, 2003; Portuguese Translations: Terapia Não-Convencional, 1991, 1975-2003 (Box 48)
    - Dutch Translations: De Machtspolitiek van Jezus Christus, 1973; Handboek Therapeutisch Handelen, 2000; Hebrew Translations: Problem-Solving Therapy. New Strategies for Effective Family Therapy, 1982; Japanese Translations: Strategies of Psychotherapy, 1973; Problem-Solving Therapy, 1985; Conversations with Milton H. Erickson, 1985; Uncommon Therapy, 1986; Conversations on Therapy. Popular Problems and Uncommon Solutions, 1993; Chinese Translations: Problem-Solving Therapy, 2003; Uncommon Therapy, 2011, 1973-2003 (Box 49)
    - Books in English: Leaving Home, 1980; Reflections on Therapy and Other Essays, 1981; The Power Tactics of Jesus Christ and Other Stories, 1986; Jay Haley on Milton H. Erickson, 1993; The Art of Strategic Therapy, with Madeleine Richeport-Haley, 2003; Directive Family Therapy with Madeleine Richeport-Haley, 2007, 1980-2007 (Box 50)
- Series 3. Haley’s Work, 1953-2004
  This series offers a view to some of Haley’s professional activities. Since he pioneered the recording of therapy sessions, and created many training films the materials on his films in this series are central to his work.
  - Subseries 3.1 Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic: memos, reports, and training programs, 1971-1975
    - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic General Memos I, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic General Memos II, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic and the Institute for Teachers of Family Therapy, (typescripts of memos, reports, and training programs), 1971-1975 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Memos reg. training from the clinic’s director Marianne Walters; Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic’s pamphlets; Materials of the Institute of Family Counseling: statistics, placement perspectus, on evaluation of students, and on new careers for teachers of family counseling., 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Committee for Human Resources: Memos and other related materials I, (typescripts), 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Committee for Human Resources: Memos and other related materials II, (typescripts), 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3.2 Conferences, Workshops, Seminars, Meetings: programs, flyers, letters, notes, and papers, 1955-2004
    - Jackson Conferences. Transcripts of Discussions Between Don D. Jackson, Jay Haley, John Weakland, and Gregory Bateson. Feb. – Apr.: 1) 2-9-55 Different Language Operations and the Related Situations of the Participants. Learning Contexts and Characters Traits. Feeling and Communication; 2) 2-16-55 The Helpless Mother & Patient’s Fear of Competing with her; 3) 2-23-55 Anxiety, Mothers and their Mothers, and Double Binds; 4) 3-16-55 Ways of Avoiding Forbidden Messages or Feelings, or Ways of Communicating Indirectly. Symptom Removal Precipitating Psychosis, and Debate on Continuity vs. Discontinuity in Mental Illness; 5) 3-23-55 The Approach to Schizophrenia; A Debate on Degree vs. Discontinuities; 6) 3-30-55 Are there Special (Exclusive) Characteristics in the Group of “Schizophrenia-P” Double Binds and Mothers?; 7) 4-6-55 Perasall Case and Double Binds. Family Background. Time in Paradoxes and Double Binds. Family Homeostasis as Double Bind Obverse; 8) 4-13-55 Jackson Interview with Mr. Earl Lane; 9) 4-20-55 J’s Patient “B” – Double Binds and Indirect Communication, “You Look Tired.” Half Truths, Suggestion and Conspiracy of Acceptance. H and Marian Barber – Potential Binds in Interviews and Ways of Therapeutic Response, i.e. Avoiding the Bind; 10) 4-27-55 Multiple Levels in Communication and Resulting Problems. Family Configuration in Etiology and Disruption on Recovery., 1955-1990 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Jackson Conferences. Transcripts of Discussions Between Don D. Jackson, Jay Haley, John Weakland, and Gregory Bateson. May – July: 11) 5-25-55 Double Binds and Two Levels Regarding Erickson’s “Stay Awake” Induction, Haley and Hackett – “Liar” or “Not True” Jackson’s “I’m a Liar or Mother is” Case, Bind “You must Obey Mother – But not Obey so I Can Criticize”; 12) 6-1-55 Hypnosis (Preparing for Erickson Trip) Double Binds and Dependence in Hypnosis and Schizophrenia; 13) 6-8-55 Double Binds: Gaubatz’ Obscure Communications and Erickson’s Handling and Inversion of Resistance to Induction; 14) 6-15-55 Open Attack on Parents Double Binds and Schizophrenia. GB Letter to Macy-Theory Regarding Logical Types, Levels, etc. Characterization of Mother or Family Structure of Schizophrenic. Hospital Structure Parallel – Schwartz on Covert Therapist-Administrator Conflict Effect on Patients; 15) 6-22-55 Report and Discussion of Conference with Erickson. A) Manic–Depressive and Schizophrenia Psychoses Compared Language Patters. Ideas on etiology and Double Binds. B) Hypnosis and Schizophrenia Compared. Induction and Etiology - “Offering” Cigarette and Amnesia. Schizophrenia as Trance? E. Takes Over Trance from Another. Double Binds: Hypnotic and Schizophrenic Responses – Kinds and Functions. “Benevolence” and Threat in Creating Binds; Illusion of Choice; 16) 6-29-55 Reinstitution of the Double Bind as a Therapeutic Move. How to Set Up and How to Alter Outcome. Similarities to Hypnosis, Especially “Artificial Neurosis.” Reinstitution and Maintenance of the Double Bind. Does Rosen “Cure” this Way? Persistence or Ending of Transference in Therapy; 17) 7-6-55 Remission: Insight and Frozen. Binds Therapists in Erickson and Others and Insight; 18) 7-14-55 Ego Splitting or Message Interpretation; 19) 7-20-55 Double Binds in Schizophrenia and in Trance Induction. Anticipation of Needs. Mothers of Schizophrenics-their Characteristics, what they Offer., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Jackson Conferences. Transcripts of Discussions Between Don D. Jackson, Jay Haley, John Weakland, and Gregory Bateson. Aug. – Oct.: 20) 8-2-55 Therapy; 21) 8-10-55 Dependency and Control; 22) Cannibalism and Orality: The Help Rejecting Complainer Classification and is Mama Fixated or the Child; 23) 8-24-55 Control, Relationship, and dependency. Attempt to Formalize Problem of Control Boo-Worthington “Reconstradiction” Material; 24) 8-31-55 Introjection, Incorporation. The Diagram of a Message Defining a Relationship. The Diagram of the Erickson Paradox; 25) 9-14-55 Therapy: Inquiry Versus Intervention, or Doing Things for the Patient; 26) 9-22-55 Rapid Psychotherapy – Asking Patient to Get Worse? Patient Keeping Secrets and Allowing this, Complimenting Oneself and Why Not; 27) 9-28-55 A Discussion of Rosen’s Interview with Arthur; 28) 10-5-55 Rosen: What to Look for on Visits? “As if” Involvement, the Rosen Controversy., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Jackson Conferences. Transcripts of Discussions Between Don D. Jackson, Jay Haley, John Weakland, and Gregory Bateson. Nov. – Dec.: 29) 11-2-55 Multiple Therapy and Rosen and Martin. Jackson Multiple Therapy Case. Controlling the Woman by Talking to Each Other, and an Emphasis on Explicit Versus Implicit Support; 30) 11-10-55 Report on Rosen Visit and Comments on Felix Tape; 31) 11-17-55 What is the Acute Phase and How Does it Differ from the Chronic Phase; 32) 11-28-55 Acute and Chronic in Terms of Stress and Anti-Stress. What is a Double Bind? Can it be Diagrammed? 33) 12-8-55 Double Binds: Patient and Stiffening Mother, and Erickson “Stay Awake.” Detailed Discussion; 34) 12-15-55 Discussion of Dependence. Dependence Versus Nurturing. Dependence Versus Domination. Biological Versus Psychological Dependency (Including Recognition of Dependency); 35) 12-22-55 Piersall Binds – Past and Wife. Dependency, Control – Especially of Distance. Voluntary-Involuntary Problems; 36) 12-29-55 Conflict over Admitting Life Can be Better than it was in Family. Sympathy Versus Distance in Sickness Device. Controlling Closeness. Langley Porter Study., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Correspondence, 1968; Conference organized by Jay Haley. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Correspondence, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Inquiries for Public Conversations, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Program and Misc., 1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Confirmation and Lists of Attendants, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: Ranking of Conference Topics, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Essay on the Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference, circa 1990; See series 8.1 box 53 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence on Conferences/Workshops: Jan. – Sept., 1969 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence on Conferences/Workshops: Sept. 1969 - Feb.1970, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence on Conferences/Workshops: March - May, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence on Conferences/Workshops: June – Dec., 1970 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence on Conferences/Workshops, 1971-1977 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Contemporary Applications of Directive Family Therapy with Adolescents and Young Adults, (typescript of description of workshop, and notes) n.d.; International Conference on Family Therapy Training, 1985, (brochure, correspondence, and typescripts of program and notes); Outlines of Family and Marital Therapy Workshops, (typescripts) n.d. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - The Evolution of Psychotherapy. Conference in Phoenix, Arizona, (booklet and program), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sexual Abuse Workshop (program, letters, and annotated typescrits), circa 1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Erickson Meeting. Erickson’s Contribution to Therapy, 1980; Technology Serving Meetings and Supervision, 1984; Directive Therapy, Cape Cod Summer Symposia, 1988, (brochure and flyers); Symposium: Schizophrenia and the Current Zeitgeist: Antitheses, 1989 “Schizophrenia: Current Myths; The Case of the Neuroleptic Drugs,” by Loren r. Mosher, (typescript of paper), circa 1980 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Outlines, Programs, and Notes of Conferences and Workshops, circa 1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Zen and the Art of Therapy Workshop, ca. 1990, (typescript of notes); Cape Cod Summer Symposia, “Directive Therapy” 1993, (booklet); Prospectus. The Evolution of Psychotherapy: A Conference. Hamburg, Germany, July, 1994, (program and correspondence); Unmuddying the Waters, Saratoga, CA, March 1995, (program, correspondence, and notes), 1990-1995 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - The Brief Therapy Conference, Brazil, 1996, (poster, booklet, program, correspondence, and typescript of Haley’s paper); New Workshop Notes: Contemporary Applications of Directive Therapy with Adolescents and Young Adults, 1996, (announcement, and notes); III European Congress on Ericksonian Hypnosis and Psychotherapy. Venice, Italy, 1998 (program); Hypnotic Voices. Workshop La Jolla, CA, 1999, (program); Directive Family Therapy with Adolescents and Young Adults, 1999, (program and correspondence), 1996 - 1999 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Abuse Workshop, (program, correspondence, and notes), 2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - The Evolution of Psychotherapy. A Conference, Anaheim, CA, “What Therapists have in Common,” Haley with discussant Arnold Lazarus. “On Common Factors in Psychotherapy: A Response to Haley,” by Arnold A. Lazarus. “Core Tasks of Psychotherapy: What Expert Therapists Do,” Donald Meichenbaum. “Millenium Therapy,” Haley’s speech on receiving the tribute., 2000 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Lecture and Workshop Notes: Brave Men Run in My Family, (typescript of incomplete paper and correspondence); Family Therapy, (typescript); Marriage Therapy, (typescript); Brief Directive Therapy for Problems at the Stages of the Family Lifecycle, (program, notes), 2000-2004 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3.3 Case Studies - Medical Records. Restricted, 1953 - 1981
    Restricted Materials
    The case studies in series 3.3 are restricted and will be available one hundred years from the date of creation (ca. 2087).
    - Case Records in Hypnotherapy A – F, (mostly handwritten notes, a few typescripts documenting sessions), circa 1958 - 1963 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Case Records in Hypnotherapy G – O), (mostly handwritten notes, a few typescripts documenting sessions), circa 1958 - 1963 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Case Records in Hypnotherapy P – S), (mostly handwritten notes, a few typescripts documenting sessions), circa 1958 - 1963 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Case Records in Hypnotherapy T – Z), (mostly handwritten notes, a few typescripts documenting sessions); misc. notes of unidentified patients, circa 1958 - 1963 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Lists of Hypnotherapy Patients and Payment Records, circa 1958 - 1963 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Results of 22 Cases in Cooperation with Another Therapist, (typescripts), 1956 - 1958 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum, 1953, (typescript); Outcome of Philadelphia Clinic Patients, 1977, (typescripts); Zen Family Report, 1981, (typescript); Analysis According to Therapist Discipline and Student, (computer printout), 1953 - 1981 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts of Family Sessions. Individuals not identified, (typescripts), 1957 - (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Research, Guidelines, Lists, Cases, (data printouts), 1984-1986 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Research Data '87: Outcome Data, (printouts), 1987 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic: Case Studies, (forms with handwritten information and letters), 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Baltimore Case Studies Outcome, (forms and statistics), 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Case Studies, 1978-1985 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Family Case, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Misc. Case Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Training Program for Clergymen or Their Designates in Family Therapy, Philadelphia, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Philadelphia Clinic. Index Forms (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3.4 Film and Audio Materials: film scripts, interview transcriptions, correspondence, grant proposals, agreements, 1953 - 2000